Guide to the Sarah Maitland Zine Collection, 1997-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sarah Maitland Zine collection 1997-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Maitland, Sarah.
4.0 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
Virginia-based writer Sarah Maitland began producing zines around 2001 and ran a zine distro for about three years. She was a founder of the Richmond Zine Fest which started in 2007. Approximately 220 titles from Sarah Maitland's personal zine collection, most dating between 1998 and 2008 and discussing a wide range of subjects. Also contains some material from Maitland's personal projects, as well as buttons, cassettes, stickers, and other ephemera.
RL.00837
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sarah Maitland Zine Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010.
Biographical Note
Virginia-based writer Sarah Maitland began producing zines around 2001 and ran a zine distro for about three years. She was a founder of the Richmond Zine Fest which started in 2007.
Collection Overview
This collection contains approximately 220 titles (some with multiple issues) from Sarah Maitland's personal zine collection, most dating between 1998 and 2008. The zines are largely about women, feminism, sexuality, and personal stories; specific subjects include feminism, sexual assault, political activism, parenting, vegan recipes, racism, bisexuality, pop culture, television shows, love, sex, mental disorders, higher education, sizism, punk rock, sex dichotomy, transgender issues, and media. Also contains some material from Maitland's personal projects, such as promotional materials from the Richmond Zine Fest, as well as buttons, cassettes, stickers, and other ephemera.
Subject Headings
Maitland, Sarah; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Abused women; Bisexuality; Comic books, strips, etc.; Fanzines; Feminism -- United States; Homosexuality; Parenting; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Racism; Self-publishing; Underground press publications -- United States; Sexual orientation; Women -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Women -- Health and hygiene -- United States; Women -- United States -- Social conditions; Women's periodicals, American; Young women -- United States -- Social life and customs
Contents of Collection
- Sarah Maitland Zine Collection, 1998-2005, (5 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
  Zines are arranged alphabetically by title. Each folder contains one issue of a zine, unless otherwise noted.
  - Zines (Box 1)
    - 2 Way Freak (Box 1)
    - 7 Layers of Recipes (Box 1)
    - 24 Pages, 24 Games (Box 1)
    - About Town (Box 1)
    - Academy Ratio (Box 1)
    - Acid Rain (Box 1)
    - The Adventures of Boxlor (Box 1)
    - All Cats are Grey in the Dark (Box 1)
    - All Slay (Box 1)
    - Almost Everyone I Love Lives in New Jersey (Box 1)
    - American Action (Box 1)
    - Are We There Yet?, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Artichoke (Box 1)
    - The Assassin and the Whiner, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - A Band of Minor Heroes, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Beautiful People (Box 1)
    - Being Red (Box 1)
    - Bejeezus, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Best Zine Ever (Box 1)
    - Big Hands, (4 issues) (Box 1)
    - Bikini Kill (Box 1)
    - Black Carrot, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Body Count/Fem-uh-nist (Box 1)
    - Booty (Box 1)
    - Brad Pitt vs. Will Smith (Box 1)
    - Brains (Box 1)
    - Brainscan, (4 issues) (Box 1)
    - Breakfast at Twilight, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Brewster, (3 issues) (Box 1)
    - Broken Pencil (Box 1)
    - Broken Records (Box 1)
    - Cartography for Beginners (Box 1)
    - Casa de los Trucos, (3 issues) (Box 1)
    - Cat and Girl, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Catch as Catch Can (Box 1)
    - Chainbreaker (Box 1)
    - Channel Seven (Box 1)
    - The Cheap Vegan, (9 issues) (Box 1)
    - Cherry Cherry Red (Box 1)
    - Chicks Rock (Box 1)
    - Child That Mind, (3 issues) (Box 1)
    - Circular (Box 1)
    - Comics and Beer (Box 1)
    - The Coming of the Second Antichrist (Box 1)
    - Comixville, (4 issues) (Box 1)
    - Compost This Zine (Box 1)
    - Confessions of a Former High School Cheerleader! (Box 1)
    - Copycat (Box 1)
    - Corrosive (Box 1)
    - Croq, (4 issues) (Box 1)
    - Cross Examination (Box 1)
    - Crude Dude (Box 1)
    - Dangeresque, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - The Day I Quit Punk Rock (Box 1)
    - Death: The Most Dirty Dance (Box 1)
    - Diamonds (Box 1)
    - D.I.Y Silkscreening (Box 1)
    - Don't Be a Scab (Box 1)
    - Do You Remember When We Felt Unstoppable? (Box 1)
    - Doris, (6 issues) (Box 1)
    - The Down, Dirty, & DIY Guide to Film and Video (Box 1)
    - Driving Blind, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Easy Zine (Box 1)
    - Eat Your Heart Out, Martha! (Box 1)
    - Electricity (Box 1)
    - The Elephant Mess (Box 1)
    - Esperanza (Box 1)
    - Every Other (Box 1)
    - Everything You've Heard is True (Box 1)
    - Evolution Comics, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Fascist Fascist (Box 1)
    - Fear of Fear (Box 1)
    - Fight Back! (Box 1)
    - The Flick Skinny, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - For the Orange Soda Kids with Paper Cut Hearts... (Box 1)
    - Forgive Me, Conrad (Box 1)
    - Forgotten Albums Best Left Forgotten (Box 1)
    - Foto (Box 1)
    - Fucktooth, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Geek the Girl (Box 1)
    - Geistenbourg Welcomes You (Box 1)
    - Getting Louder Everyday, (3 issues) (Box 1)
    - Giantess, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - Girl Conspiracy (Box 1)
    - Girl Swirl, (3 issues) (Box 1)
    - Give Me Back (Box 1)
    - Glue (Box 1)
    - Go Teen Go (Box 1)
    - Greenzine (Box 1)
    - Guilt (Box 1)
    - Gutwrench (Box 1)
    - Haircuts (Box 1)
    - Hard as Nails (Box 1)
    - Heartattack, (2 issues) (Box 1)
    - The Heart Star (Box 2)
    - Hermana, Resist, (3 issues) (Box 2)
    - High School Girls (Box 2)
    - Hit it or Quit it (Box 2)
    - Home Economics: Growing Up Like Our Grandmothers (Box 2)
    - Hope (Box 2)
    - Horizontal Stripes (Box 2)
    - Hot Pants (Box 2)
    - How to Be a Good Library Patron (Box 2)
    - How I Learned to Do IT Bloody Murder (Box 2)
    - How I Learned to Love Myself and Occasionally Other Men (Box 2)
    - I am Not a Bad Gorilla (Box 2)
    - I am the City (Box 2)
    - I Don't Like Mondays, (2 issues) (Box 2)
    - I Dreamed I Was Assertive, (2 issues) (Box 2)
    - I Hear You Like Stories! (Box 2)
    - Identity (Box 2)
    - Idiosyncrasy, (2 issues) (Box 2)
    - Indulgence (Box 2)
    - Inside the Test (Box 2)
    - The Jacquerie, The Antichrist, and Possibly a Commentary on Society as a Whole (Box 2)
    - Journal Song (Box 2)
    - The Juniper (Box 2)
    - Kitty Magik (Box 2)
    - Knock on Formica (Box 2)
    - Kyle Bravo's Punk Rock Guide to Saving Money, Fighting Capitalism, & Having Fun While You're at It (Box 2)
    - Ladyfest RVA (Box 2)
    - Larceny (Box 2)
    - Let's DIY! (Box 2)
    - A Little Guide to Truing Bike Wheels (Box 2)
    - Love Fades, (3 issues) (Box 2)
    - Love Letters to Monsters (Box 2)
    - Lovely Ugly Cruel World, (6 issues) (Box 2)
    - Lupron and Gonal-F (Box 2)
    - Make Waves (Box 2)
    - The Making of a Femme (Box 2)
    - The Managerial Guide to Beating Workers Into Submission (Box 3)
    - Maximus Tom (Box 3)
    - May Your Heart Lead You On (Box 3)
    - Media Whore, (3 issues) (Box 3)
    - Mia Zapata (Box 3)
    - Moments of Climax (Box 3)
    - Mother Rebel, (2 issues) (Box 3)
    - Mr. Ken Clean-Air System (Box 3)
    - The Ms. Films DIY Guide to Film and Video, (2 issues) (Box 3)
    - Ms. Frizz (Box 3)
    - Muppet in Training (Box 3)
    - Muse, (3 issues) (Box 3)
    - My Heart the Doormat (Box 3)
    - My Room Records (Box 3)
    - Namaste (Box 3)
    - No Better Voice, (4 issues) (Box 3)
    - Not Sorry, (2 issues) (Box 3)
    - No Snow Here, (3 issues) (Box 3)
    - Off My Jammy (Box 3)
    - On Being Jealous of Invertebrates, (4 issues) (Box 3)
    - Open All the Time (Box 3)
    - The Pac-Man Fever, (3 issues) (Box 3)
    - Paper Crush (Box 3)
    - Pets and Publishers (Box 3)
    - The Photographic Appeal (Box 3)
    - Placenta (Box 3)
    - The Playground Messiah (Box 3)
    - The Pleiades (Box 3)
    - Poetry in Motion, (2 issues) (Box 3)
    - Polaroid-Celluloid (Box 3)
    - Power Candy (Box 3)
    - Pretend It Didn't Happen and Maybe It Will Go Away (Box 3)
    - Pretty Beaver, (2 issues) (Box 4)
    - Pretty Good For A... (Box 4)
    - Quantify, (6 issues) (Box 4)
    - The Rabbit Fodder Addict (Box 4)
    - Radical Pet (Box 4)
    - Radical South (Box 4)
    - Reciprocity (Box 4)
    - Red Scare (Box 4)
    - Red-Hooded Sweatshirt, (2 issues) (Box 4)
    - Reign of Terror (Box 4)
    - A Renegade's Handbook to Love and Sabotage, (5 issues) (Box 4)
    - A Resource Guide for Anti-Racist Feminism (Box 4)
    - Riot Librarrrian (Box 4)
    - Rock Star with Purses (Box 4)
    - Rock Star with Words, (2 issues) (Box 4)
    - Root (Box 4)
    - Rotgut (Box 4)
    - A Rough Guide to Bicycle Maintenance (Box 4)
    - Schlepp (Box 4)
    - She Made This (Box 4)
    - Sisu, (3 issues) (Box 4)
    - Slug and Lettuce, (2 issues) (Box 4)
    - Sock Monkey Social Life (Box 4)
    - Someone Loves Me in Ohio (Box 4)
    - Southern Fried Darling, (1 issue and supplement) (Box 4)
    - Space (Box 4)
    - Stolen Sharpie Revolution, (2 issues) (Box 4)
    - Subject to Change (Box 4)
    - Taking Back the Night (Box 4)
    - That Girl, (3 issues) (Box 5)
    - Thermidor (Box 5)
    - These Are the Days, (2 issues) (Box 5)
    - Time Zones and State Lines (Box 5)
    - Turtle (Box 5)
    - Two By Four (Box 5)
    - The Vegan Guide to Washington D.C (Box 5)
    - VMFA's Teen Zine: Visual Tapas (Box 5)
    - The Volatile Woman (Box 5)
    - Voluntary Transaction (Box 5)
    - We Are Warriors (Box 5)
    - We Need to Eat (Box 5)
    - What Are You Still Sad About? (Box 5)
    - What's Her Deal?, (3 issues) (Box 5)
    - White Blackbirds (Box 5)
    - Wintertime (Box 5)
    - Witch-Hunt (Box 5)
    - With Heart in Mouth (Box 5)
    - Words Like Thieves (Box 5)
    - Woven (Box 5)
    - A Year in Reading (Box 5)
    - You Are Here, (2 issues) (Box 5)
    - You Live for the Fight When That's All You've Got (Box 5)
    - Your Mama's Not Home (Box 5)
    - Zine World, (2 issues) (Box 5)
  - Other materials
    - Zines, Zine Distro, and Small Record Label catalogs and pamphlets, 2000s (Box 5)
    - Fliers for Maitland's personal projects, 2000s (Box 5)
    - Fliers, stickers, and buttons, 2000s (Box 5)
    - 3 audio cassette tapes from Ego Records, 1997-2001 and undated (Box 5)
    - Fliers for Zine Fests and other projects by Maitland (Opaperfolder 1)